foreign
[Music]
episode 146. I hope you're all doing
very well
so uh today I will take questions that
you have asked in the comments with the
hashtag ask Abhijit and at the end of
the thing if I have time I will take
some live chat questions as well but
before we do that let me do my customary
greeting let's see who all is there on
the live chat with us I can say
geopolitical Dubai Prasad
Typical Gamer Akash nachiket Joshua
Deepak Kumar Manoj Kumar
uh Rita Singh aniket biswas samudra
Gupta Vladimir Aditya
Ankit Kishore
sarthak Saddam Hussein
foreign
Melvin K8 991 gaming Ronald
system tools librand detector
thermocratic sushant Gupta
technician Rahul Rustin Cole madixxai
asmenor Minato Namikaze Ankit Kumar
uh siddhant
Raj Kumar Vladimir vladimirovich Putin
dude
Aryan samarth Arpita and lots and lots
of other people
great to see you all on the live show uh
I could go on forever but yeah I think
we should uh
and lots of other people so uh with that
said I uh will now start with the
questions that you all have asked and
let me see how many I can take during
the session so excuse me all right okay
let's begin
so what's question number one
Golden State 2002 says could you talk
about Buddha and his race many whites
are saying that he is skition and blonde
haired blue eyed now well how does he
become blue-eyed and blonde haired now
he was a historic
historical person who lived about two
and a half thousand years ago that's
what that's the best estimate that we
have and uh so what did it look like
so uh Gautam Buddha as we know was born
in Northern India Lumbini it's now
currently
part of Nepal yeah but historically it's
always been part of India yes right so
he was born in Northern India he lived
his life there he preached you know he
he gave his sermons all across Northern
India in eastern India and he died in
the city of kushinagar that's that's
where he passed away right
and uh the Buddhist texts tell us a lot
about what he looked like and all
there's a whole set of uh
characteristics that are described in
which it is said that it looks like it
he he had blue eyes
so that's not extremely surprising there
are lots of people in India who have
blue eyes it's it's a
recessive characteristic genetic
characteristic blue eyes yes I remember
a couple of months ago I was in a hotel
whose manager had blue eyes you know
striking blue eyes and he was Indian
proper Indian
there are there are people in India I
mean I would say most likely less than
one percent of Indians would have blue
eyes and there are other eye colors also
in India green eyes and gray eyes and
all those hazel eyes whatever else yeah
blue eyes is quite uh rare but yes you
do have people who have blue eyes in
India in Northern India in Western India
in in Gujarat in in Rajasthan in in the
Maharashtra as well I am sure even in
Kerala you will find people with blue
eyes even in Sri Lanka you will find
people with blue eyes and so on yeah so
you do find people with Duos that
doesn't mean that that these people are
so-called white people the so-called
white race and once again you also find
people in India who have blonde hair
you find people who have red hair also
in India it's it's quite rare but you do
find these characteristics also India
has incredible genetic diversity so as
far as we know Gotham Buddha had blue
eyes I mean some some versions of of his
description in some in some reports or
some writings
it is in some accounts he is described
as having blue eyes so maybe he had blue
eyes there is no account that describes
him as having or blonde hair or hair
that is not dark right
and skin color I'm not sure maybe light
light brown or something must have been
the skin color that's typical of people
who live in Northern India yes now about
him being skeetian
so the scithians first of all we have to
understand are an ancient people nomadic
people who lived across Eurasia Europe
and Asia and uh they were of Indian
origin they lived in the places that in
the regions that were then called
uttarakuru and uttar
uttarakuru was a present-day xinjiang in
Tibet more or less present day yes and
uttara madra was present day Uzbekistan
Pakistan all of that Central Asia what
is now called Central Asia the scythians
lived there and they were of Indian
origin themselves
of course in European descriptions they
are described as having blue eyes and
blonde hair
well Gotham Buddha is described as as
having Eastern Asian features when you
see statues in in China and and Mongolia
and Japan Etc in India he's described as
having Indian features because there was
Indian and so on so people will will
shape their perception of history
based on what they look like but this
kid and the best genetic analysis that
has been done of various remains
uh tells us that they were of Indian
origin R1 A1A even the cushions yes
that's their petrolineal genetic lineage
and the scithians on average the the
average kitten had light brown skin
brown eyes and dark hair
yeah and they were like reasonably tall
so that's what kittens looked like now
the truth is the fact is that the
scithians did in progress into India
they did enter India this their entry
their re-entry rather into India
happened around 150 BC
now Gotham Buddha lived around 500 BC
roughly roughly give or take yeah so
this kitchens reappear in India I mean
they appear in India as Invaders and
conquerors uh about 350 years after
Gotham Buddha died roughly give it let's
say three centuries after he died so
while he was alive there were no kittens
in India the shakas and yes we know what
he is called one of the one of the the
epithets used for remote terms used for
him is
the word Shakira sounds very much like
sakka or Shaka which is the term that
the Indians and Iranians the the we used
for the scithians the Indians called
this kittens the Shaka and the the our
Persian cousins called them the sucker
right but that's not shakya that's
different
so even I many years ago used to believe
that the Gotham Buddha may have been
because he's called shakyamuni but it's
not shakamuni or sakamuni is shakyamuni
now the shakyas were a warrior Clan
in Northern India right the shakya uh
Dynasty the clan there were three years
there were warriors they were royalty
yes so that's why he was called
shakyamuni because he was a Muni he was
a monk he was a not a warrior he chose
not to be a warrior he chose to be a
monk and all that whatever we know the
story so that's why they called him
shakimoni he was not a kitten monk he
was not of scithian extractions lineage
he was a northern Indian lineage so it's
completely wrong to say that but Gotham
Buddha was a white person with blue eyes
maybe he had blue eyes but he certainly
did not have white characteristics and
features in blonde hair now why is this
is this question a reason I'll show you
why this question has arisen uh let me
show you uh how Gautam Buddha is being
described these days uh using artificial
intelligence
you know reconstruction so this is a
person whoever it is saying who says
that I finally trained mid-journey AI to
draw a proper Buddha and according to
this lady this is what a proper Buddha
should look like this individual looks
like the Greco-Roman descriptions of
various Sports people right
uh and and she she uh tries to justify
what she's done by saying that most
people have been extremely positive but
to the handful of fools complaining
about Buddha depicted as white two
points first he is descended from
kitchens and in Pali he's described as
having as being pale with blue eyes and
secondly the Japanese depict decisions
as Japanese so got a problem with that
so this is not any kind of justification
I mean it's not her fault that the AI is
thrown out this image maybe she is given
certain prompts that made uh this
depiction of apparently Buddha look like
uh he is of Greco Roman extraction so
in Bali he's described described as
being pale with blue eyes well uh the PA
in Pali I would be described as being
pale with brown eyes that doesn't make
me a white person if I had blue eyes
that would not make me a white person
and secondly the Japanese describe Jesus
is Japanese so I mean what sort of
argument is that so the problem is that
these days there's a lot of AI art
coming out yeah and the problem with AI
art is that it's all biased even the see
what is artificial intelligence
artificial intelligence is is a neural
network it's it's a set of programs and
algorithms yeah that you have to train
you have to train the these AIS with
data lots of data in case it's a it's uh
an AI that uh that outputs text you have
to train it with millions and millions
of is you know uh
examples of text and then slowly over
time it's able to recognize how language
is formed and so on so forth and then
you have these AI chat Bots these days
that that talk to you as if they're a
real person and they sound quite
intelligent and people are really
enamored with this right now yeah it's
it's a fad that's going on right now and
of course we have all of these uh AI
image generators that are throwing out
all these images and the the problem is
that the the data that these AIS are
trained on is all data that that has
been fed to them by their Western
trainers so when it comes to throwing
out images of Indians it's gonna be
biased it's gonna be more eurocentric
right and and let me give you some other
examples here's uh so P Indians are are
having fun with the with this AI uh
image generators and all that so here is
a see whatever is being shown here uh
it's all generated by AI it's not
generated by the person
who has tweeted this so so if you are
upset about the images please do not
direct direct any hate towards the
person who has tweeted this okay they
are just playing with the thing and they
are showing they're tweeting well the
the kind of images they're getting so
this is apparently Prince Siddharth
Gotham of shakya Clan once again so you
know so in in the top left image he is
shown as having feathers in his hair
because I'm sure the air was told to to
uh output an image of an Indian person
so for AIS that are trained in the West
Indian means Native American right so
you see lots of these depictions of of
Indian historical figures having
having feathers in in their headgear and
yeah so this is a kind of stereotyped uh
depiction of uh Siddhartha Gotham these
are apparently more realistic portraits
of Prince Siddharth Gotham age 25
married and all and so on uh final
attempt at Prince Siddharth Gotham uh
yeah blue eyes sure but yeah this this
these these depictions look more Indian
and somewhat more realistic I would say
yeah and here's more so now uh these are
AI depictions of historical figures like
Lord Rama so this is Lord Rama according
to AI Lord Rama and Lord lakshman the
two the two brothers yes and can you see
this strange cross inverted cross or
whatever it is on their foreheads I mean
how is that in Indian cultural
characteristic yeah so these are the
problems that you find that you see you
know when you see ai ai generated images
about of Indian uh historical figures
and culture here's another this is a
lord jumbo one wearing a very strange
almost
almost uh the the the cape or or dress
that he is wearing reminds me of what
Christian Cardinals you know Catholic
Cardinals would wear and even the the
headgear the crown isn't Indian at all
here is apparently Lord lakshman uh
sorry Lord Hanuman well why does he have
once again that face paint that is that
is typical or stereotypical of Native
Americans because the Native Americans
are called Indians right in in the U.S
and in much of the western world yeah so
once again this is problematic and this
again I'm not sure how to how to
characterize this you know this image
again foreign
this is something that you would see in
a movie like The Planet of the Apes or
something yeah and this is angad so I do
not blame the Indians the people who are
playing with this AI image generators
the problem is that these AI generators
image generators and text generators Etc
were trained on very biased data sets
here let's see some more examples this
is a very interesting uh Twitter account
yeah so this this looks a little more
historically and culturally accurate or
appropriate this is what a man of Gupta
age would most likely or perhaps have
looked like perhaps yes certainly the
physical features the the facial
features look definitely Indian this is
what the honik Invaders of India would
have looked like this well the honig
Invaders of India would have looked more
Eastern Asian not uh the stereotypical
caucasoid look that you see here so this
is a fail from the AI yeah
uh this is what the greco-back train
Kings the indo-greek Kings would have
looked like possibly but why do they
have feathers in their hair once again
like the stereotypical Native Americans
This is again a problem and and the kind
of dread the clothing he's wearing is
more European than anything you would
ever see ever in India right
this is what the suckers would have
looked like in those kethians the the
Invaders well perhaps perhaps not we're
not quite sure this person looks like uh
a present-day person who lives in
Central Asia you know a mixture of
Indian characteristics and Central Asian
turkey characteristics so these AI image
generators and then this is a lady from
an Indian woman from the early British
Raj definitely the Indian ladies from
that time would wear such clothes and
the facial features are very much Indian
and this is a person from pretty student
Ireland sure all right so these are some
examples and this is the kind of fun
that people have with AI this is what AI
is good at you know uh not it's still
not good at historical reconstruction so
it's good for playing these weird funny
games and all you know uh this is an
example of open ai's chat GPT uh it is
not willing to make the basic inference
on who was responsible for the Bengal
famine yeah these language models are
the next version of Wikipedia encoding
hard structural biases under the guise
of neutrality so the question that was
asked to AI open AIS chat GPD is who was
responsible for the great Bengal famine
and it says it was a combination of
factors including drought and War
related disruption blah blah blah blah
British colonial policies it's not
accurate to say that a single individual
or group was responsible solely
responsible uh and then it's questioned
further and yes it refuses to to hold
the British accountable further then the
very more specific question was there a
British politician head of government
who had the ability to change the
British foreign policy and so on uh so
it goes around and around around Winston
Churchill but does not hold Winston
Churchill responsible so that's the kind
of bias everyone knows that Winston
Churchill is the monster who killed more
than 4 million bengalis deliberately
it was an artificially engineered famine
done it was it was done at the behest of
Winston Churchill that monster who is
responsible for the genocide of more
than 4 million Indians bengalis right
Indians of course
and yet this uh thing is is unwilling to
tell you about that it's unwilling to
recognize what really happened so that's
bias that is clear bias now uh on my
channel I think more than a year ago I
spoke about uh algorithm bias right so
let's search for it I'll go read them
Rhythm bias in case see I've got more
than a thousand videos on my channel and
many of the questions I've already
answered so this is how you can search
for something that you may want to look
for so here is a a video more than a
year ago from episode 27 of Oscar budget
yeah algorithm bias how can AI be
manipulated so in case you want to
understand how AIS can be manipulated
and how they can be biased take a look I
mean watch this video it's less than
five minutes long yeah in which I've
spoken about how this is done so uh
that's the deal so the truth about
Gautam Buddha in his race is that he was
Indian the problem is
the Indian education system in any other
country if such a question would would
be asked about one of the historical
figures the questioner would be laughed
at yeah
I mean if if somebody would claim that
that uh like like in our case it is
being said that Gotham Buddha was white
let's say somebody makes the claim that
Julius Caesar was black or every single
Italian person man woman and little
child would laugh at that person but in
the case of India Indians are wondering
because somebody made the Gotham Buddha
look white so what was the race we don't
even know the truth about our history it
is the Fault squarely that it is the it
is squarely the fault of the Indian
education system and our history
teachers and our history textbooks they
are to blame for this it should it this
is this is something that should be
laughed at this is laughable it's
risible it's asinine that somebody has
portrayed Lord Buddha Gotham Buddha as a
white person it's nonsense it's utter
nonsense and yet when someone does it we
get confused we Indians uh start
questioning ourselves that was it true
was he white what nonsense it is the
fault of the Indian education system
that people have this question and
people are so confused and and full of
self-doubt so I hope I have thrown some
light on what this entire thing is about
yeah okay let's move on to the next next
question
says what's your opinion on AI art is it
ethical I've heard many artists claim uh
that about art theft and cyber bullying
how will art be affected in the future
uh yeah AI art is a problem you know so
these AI is they're trained to Output
art by feeding them millions of images
images of art images of classical
painters like Picasso and uh not Mozart
sorry uh Picasso and and whoever else
you know
Vincent van Gogh
and lots of other painters you know
painters from from mainly from Europe
but also are from other parts of the
world I suppose which would be in a
small minority in the overall context
yeah and even lots of Modern Art is
being fed into these AI uh for in order
to train the AIS so art that is scraped
off the internet yeah let's say you go
to let's say you do a Google search
let's do it shall we let's do a Google
Search and uh
let's just do a modern paintings
modern paintings or Modern Art
Modern Art
and we go here and lots of these images
that you'll find on Google image search
will be images that are created by
modern artists yes 21st century artists
and it's so easy to scrape these images
off of Google uh image search and feed
them into AIS and then the AI is what
they do
and is that they then are able to
reproduce the same style as that of
modern artists so if you if you tell the
AI paint an image of a dog playing
snooker in the style of so-and-so artist
who may be alive today maybe a young
artist then the AI will produce art that
looks exactly like what this specific
individual would paint
so that is incredibly problematic so it
would so now that AI has become so good
at producing art it's it it there's the
real possibility that it's going to uh
put lots of artists out of business and
it's uh yeah you know
it could constitute in some ways our
theft because you're producing the exact
same style as so and so person let's say
I'm an artist every artist has their own
style of painting or whatever it is then
the AI could be if you if you let's say
I'm an I'm a painter a digital painter
modern painter yeah I create I create
digital art and I have let's say 50
works of art that are available online
but they they belong to me the copyright
belongs to me so the AI can be fed that
that data is input and then it will be
able to start outputting anything in my
style
which essentially puts me out of
business forever yeah so that is very
problematic so yes many AI uh many
artists have have pointed this out that
this is a extremely unethical and it's a
we will I mean we will need to to
formulate some kind of copyright
guidelines or something like that which
uh prevents this from happening because
right now it's it's a free for all there
are no laws there are no rules nothing
and you can just scrape millions of
images of the internet and feed it into
your AI and then the AI will do can can
essentially put artists of the business
now ai is able to produce incredible art
all kinds of art anything
that you can anything that you can
imagine it's able to produce it it can
produce lots of different versions and
iterations of whatever you can imagine
so yeah it's it's uh
it could actually uh
you know put painters out of business
and that's bad that's bad so right now
there are no Solutions but somebody
needs to find a solution people need to
get together think about this properly
and and formulate the right solutions
for this
okay Angel Dust says seriously is there
any society where there is no
discrimination wake up it's human nature
disappointed in you so this person is
disappointed in me and I think the
context is uh the fact that I pointed
out about uh the the the incidents the
very high incidence of discrimination
and racism in Israel yeah
so in response to that uh this person
say listen first of all no hate to
anybody people have their own uh
perspective and all that so we got to
respect that so so the the what this
person is saying is indeed true there is
absolutely no Society in the entire
Multiverse where there is no
discrimination there is no Society see
people believe that there should be
equality in the world that is absolute
nonsense equality is unnatural
there can be no equality in the world
there can be equality of opportunity but
that there can never be equality of
outcome which would be extremely
counterproductive if you try to achieve
equality of outcome you know if you try
to engineer inequality of outcome
why do I say there is that equality is
unnatural
have you seen two human beings who are
exactly the same who are exactly equal
in everything some people are tall some
are short some are muscular some are
skinny some are intelligent some are
less intelligent some are athletic some
are very unathletic and so on and so
forth everybody has certain a set of
skills and talents and some things that
they are deficient in right that's
that's just how it is everybody is
unequal nobody is equal
you cannot equate two people everyone's
unique look at animals you think you can
you equate a rabbit with a with a boa
constrictor with a crocodile with a lion
with a parrot with a with a tortoise
with an ostrich doesn't work like that
everybody is different every species
different within a species if you if you
look at tigers if you take seven eight
different Tigers they will all be
different they will all have different
characteristics and what is what are
sporting competitions all about where we
are witnessing the World Cup football
World Cup right now what is it about is
it a celebration of equality no it's a
celebration of inequality now
discrimination is an inequality are a
whole different thing now obviously in
every society you will have
discrimination
and the the this person is uh definitely
upset about the fact that I pointed out
that there is so much discrimination in
Israeli Society and the implication
seems to be perhaps that the first
introspect and look at Indian Society
well let me tell you
the problem once again boils down to the
education system we are taught so many
lies about India about our own history
all your education all your history
textbooks just look at who wrote them
who are the individuals who wrote your
history textbooks
and what what what were their political
inclinations like what were their
agendas like it's quite transparent
the entire Indian education system has
been under the Stranglehold
of
essentially anti-indian forces since the
1960s and 70s essentially since British
times right essentially since since
British types they have all been biased
against India they have had in this
agenda to portray India as regressive as
misogynistic as as all those bad things
they could think about as a backward
Society is a primitive barbaric society
and so on so forth yes
an inequality discrimination castism all
that nonsense yes that's how every
single textbook will teach you and
that's why you are filled with these
ideas and when I come and tell you that
it's not the case you tell me that
you're stupid I am stupid
disappointed in your budget because
you're telling us something about
textbooks don't tell us
well the problem is you have not studied
enough history look at how Indian
history has been depicted over the
centuries
look at how the Greeks wrote about India
two and a half thousand years ago look
at how the Chinese wrote about India
their the Chinese word for India was
chanchu the center of Heaven
yeah why why would they call another
Nation the center of Heaven
a give it a status above their own why
why did everybody flock to India to get
knowledge why did the Japanese write so
so well about India whether the Chinese
write so well about India the Chinese
have always had this culture of
superiority and yet they called India
tianju the center of Heaven
the Greeks wrote so so well about India
the Persians wrote so well about India
even the Europeans when they first came
to India about 500 or so years ago wrote
so so wrote about India in such
incredibly glowing terms
that the Indian family system is the
best family system in the world far
better than anything Europe can can can
Europe has European Society has it's
only once the missionaries
came started coming into India that's
when the portrayal changed it took it
was a complete 180 degree term and
that's when they started suddenly
creating this atrocity literature you
haven't studied sufficient history
that's why you don't you don't you're
not able to see this chronology yes
and lots of Indian Scholars have written
about this look at the works of
Meenakshi and Dr Meenakshi Jain who has
been on the on on this channel uh at
least once at least yeah
yeah so uh I would suggest please study
history
properly
you have I see listen I am not trying to
say that I know all of history no I'm
still learning history I'm still
learning history I'm I'm still a student
I'm still figuring things out but it is
possible that I have I may have studied
a little more history than than the
person who's asking this question
possibly perhaps perhaps he or she knows
more than me in which case they can give
actual uh evidence
but the truth is that India if you
compare all the civilizations in the
world India has been the fairest of them
all with the least possible
discrimination yes and now if you want
to talk about discrimination the the
this uh comment came in one of the
videos in which I spoke about Israel
right you know what the truth is
the truth is
that there is more discrimination
against Jews
in Israel today
then there has ever been in India
in the past two and a half to two and a
half thousand years
Jews first came into India maybe two or
two thousand years ago or slightly
before that
and they have lived in India Jews for
more than two thousand years there has
never ever been anti-jewish anti-semitic
discrimination in India ever
and in Israel today I can give you a
thousand examples of discrimination
against Jews since we are talking about
this why don't I do it why don't I show
it yeah so I've spoken about this before
let me give you some more examples this
is
Indian Jews in Israel it wasn't the
promised land so if you read this
article you can see the link the the the
URL you can Google it yes Indian Jews in
Israel it wasn't the promised land there
is a lot of discrimination in Israel
against Indian origin Jews they are Jews
they are your brothers sisters and yet
you discriminate against them why why
isn't Israel the the promised land for
all Jews if it is so then why is there
discrimination against Indian origin
Jews here is another the murder of a
young Menasha immigrant this is a
Northeast Indian Jew yes from from
turachanpur District of Manipur so these
people they believe they are Jewish and
they have been allowed by the by the
Israelis to come and migrate to Israel
and then good God the kind of
discrimination and racism they are
facing these Jews these Indian origin
Jews here is one more Indian lost
India's Jewish lost tribe faces hard
times in Israel read this article right
here is more
breaks silence to protest subjugation
subjugation to NGO controlling their
Alia terrible yes intimidation to
silence detractors and so on
assessing the racism that exists towards
the Menasha Community these are Indian
origin Jews terrible terrible
discrimination they are called China
China
and they're ridiculed and they're
assaulted and they're beaten up and
they're murdered yes in Israel
it's not only the the Indian origin Jews
in Israel some Jews are more equal than
others Ethiopian Jews have suffered
discrimination by the Israeli state
which has been intelligent enough to
divide ethnic groups to ensure there
will never be a joint fight against them
so this is being done at the state level
not at the People to People level this
is institutionalized discrimination and
racism in Israel right against their own
people against their own their own
Jewish people Israel gave birth control
to Ethiopian Jews without their consent
both controlled sterilized
you know the Israel has admitted for the
first time it has been it has been
giving Ethiopian Jewish immigrants birth
control injections often without their
knowledge or consent yes
uh
and so on so when did this stop I wonder
the government had previously denied the
practice but the Israeli health
ministries director General has now
ordered gynecologists to stop
administering the drugs which year was
this 2013. so in 2013 they officially
asked the gynecologist to stop
administering the drugs without the
knowledge or consent or the of the
victims so until 2013 at least this was
going on as a state policy
yeah because Ethiopian origin Jews are
are dark skinned they're not white right
so it's fine they should not reproduce
they should not be able to reproduce
there's more little hope of change for
Israel's marginalized groups once again
Ethiopian Israeli protectors protesters
are arrested in Jerusalem so you can
read this
Ethiopian Jews confront racism in Israel
Middle East policy Council
um
of the Israel or how the Israeli Army's
racist system harmed hundreds of
thousands of mizrahim the Mizrahi Jews
are the brown skin Jews the the real
Jews the original Jews and they are
about 45 percent of Israel's population
and 45 of your population you are racist
against them can you believe the the
incredible what's going on in Israel yes
so you can read the article about how
these really Army's racist system it's a
systemic systemic thing it harmed
hundreds of thousands of Mizrahi Jews
yes but Legacy of racism towards the
brown-skinned uh original Jews yeah
terrible terrible
there are riots Israel State Rabbi
spread racism in the name of Judaism the
rejection of Ethiopian Israelis Jewish
identities you know people tell me that
the Israelis have been so good they went
to Africa and they rescued the Ethiopian
origin Jews of black skin Jews and
that's wonderful they've made news about
that and then see what happens when they
reach Israel
horrible
State Rabbi spreads racism in the name
of Judaism
we saw Jews with hearts like Germans
Moroccan immigrants in Israel warned
from families not to follow so there
were Jews in Morocco as well there may
still be perhaps so they migrated to
Israel and then based on the kind of
treatment that was meted out to them
they want their families not to follow
not to come to Israel stay in Morocco
even though it's a Muslim majority place
it is better for you to stay in Morocco
than to come to Israel just imagine that
so these are a few examples a few
examples I can I can do a three-hour
session and and show you hundreds of
examples that is how incredibly racist
and discriminatory Israeli Society is
and the Israeli State itself is against
its own people not against the
Palestinians not not against people of a
non-abrahamic religion against their own
Jewish people
so am I wrong to point this out
yeah
and what and it is true that every
society has some level of discrimination
but overall if you look at Indian
Society it has been the least
discriminatory Society the fairest
Society of all society in which
everybody could Prosper for thousands of
years what happened in the past 1000
years is that India was again under
foreign occupation
India Society was mangled and distorted
it was driven to Despair and when a
society cannot function the way it has
evolved to function all kinds of uh you
know
distortions and and evil practices bad
practices will creep into the society
from outside yes
but I have spoken about this multiple
times so I'm not gonna go on about this
but the truth is that India Society has
always been the least discriminative
Society in the entire world right now
India Society is is coming out of a
thousand years
of of destruction of wholesale
destruction the worst genocide human
history has ever seen so it will take
time for society to readjust itself even
right now we are under Colonial laws
yes Hindu phobic laws
uh laws that that would that seek and
and governance system and institutions
that seek to eradicate Indian culture
from India yeah so that's what India is
up against so let's not blame the
victims let's blame the actual
oppressors to who have distorted and
destroyed Indian society and made it
what it is yeah India Society like I've
said It suffers from two things It
suffers from PTSD post-traumatic stress
disorder and it also suffers from
amnesia so it doesn't people don't know
why societies has been distorted like
this so they tend to blame themselves so
it's so easy to make Indians feel
ashamed of themselves that your Society
is this and that and all that and that's
what what they've been doing and that's
why they ensure that the education
system teaches you lies your teachers
teach you lies your textbooks teach your
lies your government teaches your lies
your leaders teach your lies tell you
lies
they glorify the wrong people yeah and
the result is a society that is totally
brainwashed totally mentally colonized
and a society that is ashamed of their
own culture
so please
educate yourselves educate yourselves
about what the truth is right let's move
on from here
okay says
um recently the West has tagged a price
cap on Russian crude oil by 60 a barrel
they said if any country doesn't follow
this they will not be allowed to use
tankers of EU NATO and Australia now
India and China are the big big clients
of Russian crude oil and this will
affect us should India and China not
cooperate with each other on this issue
and should not all the Asian countries
cooperate together work together to uh
to overcome the dollar dominance like
India Iran China Russia see Nations that
is uh Southeast Asian Nations perhaps
Central Asian Nations combined we are
about 60 of the world's global
population if we do so even the West
cannot sanction us that will make them
inclusive yeah so the West is trying to
impose these arbitrary oil price gaps
and all that who the hell are they to
decide
to at what price somebody should sell
and buy oil yeah but they're trying to
do that this is this is called arm
twisting this is called blackmail
so what's happening right now is
possibly
a move towards d-dollarization right now
the U.S the the the
basis of the U.S hegemony
over the world is the fact is the US
Dollars uh Reserve currency status it is
the world's reasonable Reserve currency
the Petro dollar so if the world or some
section or some portion of the world
let's say 50 of the world where to move
away from the dollar then that would be
a severe setback
to to the this uh to the Anglo-Saxon
Saxon hegemony on the world and that's
what various Nations seem to be moving
towards the brics plus plus the brics
plus grouping right now it's just bricks
but many nations have expressed their
desire to join the brics grouping
and if that happens and if the brics
grouping comes up with its own Reserve
currency that is not
tied to death that is not based on
promises for false promises and just
debt but it is actually uh based on gold
in a basket of commodities
gold and oil and and graphite and
uranium and whatever else yeah various
metals and salt then that currency will
actually have some real value and if our
section A significant section of the
world adopts that then um it'll be uh
it'll be a significant challenge to the
uh old Anglo-Saxon hegemonic World Order
yes but yeah it is very hard for Nations
like India and China to come together to
come to an agreement and cooperate when
you see the the the nature of the
Chinese Empire the China the Chinese are
an Empire it's an imperial power yes
it's an imperial power with hegemonic
ambitions of its own that's what China
is and they
uh they they also seek Indian Territory
they lay claims on more Indian Territory
and there is this history since the
1950s of Confrontation between India and
China we know the history so it's very
hard for these two Nations to trust each
other and yet they will have to if they
want to make this happen they're going
to have to find a way so maybe the
Russians can mediate between India and
China whatever but uh India and China
essentially cannot cooperate until the
Border issue is settled and the Chinese
have shown no science of doing that they
have been holding that as a democracy
sword on or the head of India and so on
so yeah big big challenges but if a
bunch of Nations come together and the
other thing is that if if the brics
grouping actually takes off and it
becomes larger then there is always the
danger that the Chinese will try to
dominate The Thing the entire Coalition
the entire grouping and use it for their
own benefit yeah
use it to further their own hegemonic
expansionist imperialist agenda
typically in a coalition of nations in a
grouping of Nations the most powerful
Nation essentially hijacks or takes over
the whole grouping and uses the grouping
to further its own geopolitical
interests so that is always a danger
when when you have a grouping that
includes China so for that to be offset
we would need India and Russia to
cooperate together and counterbalance
China maybe even Iran but but the
Iranians don't really see China as a
threat because they don't have a common
border with China so the Iranians may
not be so so inclined to working with
Russia in India to counter by China the
two Nations that have large borders with
China currently are Russia and India so
these two Nations see China as a threat
whether they say it or not so there's
this entire thing happening right now
but yes I would say that the Asian
Nations
should cooperate and find and create a
new system a parallel system A system
that will compete with the Petro dollar
system even the Saudis want to join
brics that would be a major blow to the
petrol dollar if they actually come and
become a part of brics yeah
and right now uh very recently Xi
Jinping president Xi Jinping visited
Saudi Arabia he had uh he held a China
Arab Nations Summit he met the various
leaders there it's including the king
king Salman and Muhammad bin Salman and
so on so yeah
so China is is kind of taking the
initiative and they are doing it
obviously for their own interests so
there are so many uh different angles
and different parameters that you have
to take into account when all of this uh
when you analyze all this so it would be
great if all these different nations
come together but that typically happens
when there is one major dominant power
that makes them come together right now
China is not that dominant yes it is
definitely the number two economy in the
world but nobody trusts China and
everyone is scared of China especially
it's the Nations which have common uh
which have boundaries with China and
China has bordered disputes boundary
disputes with almost all its neighbors
so yeah that's a that's a tough
situation that we are all in if China
were not that hegemonic imperialistic
imperialistic and expansionist power
then it would make things so much easier
but that's the way they are so we're
gonna have to see what happens whether
the the leaders of these nations are
able to find a way
ideally but see right now India is not
that large in economy uh
it is the fifth largest economy in the
world also maybe in the next five years
it will become the third largest economy
yeah it will overtake Germany and Japan
it's it's a matter of time it's only
when India Rises to a certain level to
at least I would say 10 trillion dollars
economy yeah that's when India would
become a major force in its own right
and be able to possibly counterbalance
China on its own without Russian help
possibly so uh the way forward for India
right now is to rise to rise
economically because with economic rise
with economic muscle comes military
muscle proportionally and so on so yeah
that's the situation it would be great
if all the nations come together but it
is right now difficult because people
don't trust China nobody trust China but
they do seek the economic benefits that
China can provide so that's the kind of
Catch 22 we are in the Nations that
don't have borders with China are more
open to collaborating and cooperating
but for us like Nations like India and
Russia it is they have to be much more
careful that's where we are and that's
that's the situation that the U.S can
take benefit of you know to keep these
nations fighting
to ratchet up the threat perceptions and
so on so there's so much there are so
many games that are being played right
now there's a whole Ukraine angle as
well
that's where we are
they just says what qualified zelinski
for for for becoming time magazines Man
of the Year 2022. and Daniel says uh
what has president volody achieved to be
named time magazines person of the year
Russia is fighting it out conquering
Ukrainian territory while this man is
only doing lip service how is he helping
Ukrainian civilians in doing this see
when it comes to okay let's see let's uh
see Time magazine's tweet uh what did
they say about Mr uh
uh let's put that on the screen yes
uh Time magazine's announcement
so this is what they said times 2022
person of the year it's no longer Man of
the Year it's person of the year which
is fine
in the spirit of Ukraine
so they have announced that he is the
the person of the year and that's what
it is the question is what has it done
to to deserve this
see when it comes to
to receiving a western award
what qualifies you for receiving a
western award is what service have you
provided to the West that is what
qualifies you to receive a western node
whether it is the uh Time person of the
year or the Pulitzer Prize or the booker
Prize or or whatever the Nobel Peace
Prize or whatever else it is
um what if you win this prize it means
that you have offered significant
services to the West that have you know
and that's the reward you get so valade
hasn't served the people of Ukraine he
has served the west and you know
sometimes a meme tells you a thought the
meme is more important I mean it is more
uh it communicates more than you could
communicate with with words so take a
look at this meme
so that's the service Mr zelinski has
provided if you remember Afghanistan the
U.S occupied Afghanistan for the best
part of two decades if not more
Afghanistan the U.S occupation
Afghanistan was a massive money
laundering operation and obviously it
served to
um to uh benefit the military-industrial
complex of the US
and a similar kind of thing is happening
in Ukraine
possibly a lot of money laundering maybe
some some of the stuff as well
is is offering a significant service to
the West they wish to break up Russia
eventually you know partition Russia
fragment Russia destroy Russia as a
nation as a culture so zelinski can help
them do that you know by by enrolling uh
the Russians in in this war and if you
can drag the war for the next three four
five years ten years then it can
hopefully bleed Russia the Russian
economy in the nation and hopefully
destroy it so zelinski is is helping the
West uh
further their agenda of destroying
Russia because they see Russia as a
major threat the Chinese possibly they
think that we can handle the Chinese but
Russia is is a much bigger threat
apparently right and in the past they
have done similar things as well yeah
this is Time magazine's Man of the Year
1931 uh it was Mr Mohandas Gandhi I mean
what service did he render to India I
wonder he delayed India's independence
for more than 20 years yes but that's
precisely the service he rendered to the
West Mr Gandhi so this is not the first
time
a leader of this quality has been given
an award for services rendered to the
West the the the West
are Past Masters in doing this they
create a fake leader prop that person up
Elevate that person to Legendary status
and then give these fake Awards to make
uh the the the
gullible citizens of the nation feel
that yes this person is really indeed
truly great that's what the West has
done again and again and again and they
are still in the process of doing such
things including possibly in places like
India you know propping up various
leaders creating new leaders out of thin
air
I'm not taking any names so please don't
accuse me of I am saying this or that I
am saying nothing they are doing this in
lots of countries you know propping up
various politicians and and portraying
portraying them as as great
revolutionary leaders it's happening in
lots of places this is what they do it
is standard it is the standard operating
procedure modus operandi right so Mr
zelinsky essentially has done nothing
really to deserve this what he has done
is he has rendered this massive service
to the West he is on on call 24x7
anytime he's needed to make a statement
he will come and make a statement I
think he makes video statements every
day if I'm not mistaken and it will
typically have lots of green screens
around him and 15 different camera
angles and I will say we're in the same
the the military dress every day and say
whatever he is whatever script is handed
out to him
so that's the kind of uh service Mr
zelinski is is he's an actor he's good
at this he's really good at this so
that's the service he's offering and for
that in in recognition of the service
to reward him for his service he has
been given this award times person of
the year and there was this Vogue photo
shoot also right in which he and his
wife posed for for the for the cover of
Vogue magazine and all that so yeah
that's what it is
The Ultimate Warrior says how can such a
constrained economy be able to invent
such things I suspect it's he's
referring to North Korea yes this
technology uh and obviously the
technology he's referring to is nuclear
technology and and ballistic missile
technology ICBM technology
InterContinental balance uh the
accordions the North Koreans have a
whole family now of ballistic missiles
the note dong the rodong the Hua song
The Hua song 17 is the latest massive
missile it's a it's an intercontinental
ballistic missile that they have tested
recently they've also conducted six or
seven nuclear tests yes at various
points in time uh so the question is
that how can such a constrained economy
invent such things this technology is
definitely been being provided by China
and it could be a threat to India as
well North Korea is a China funded
puppet country whose existence is to be
used to go on to war with major
supervisors and sacrifice itself if
needed to take the blade but take the
blame away from China That's what be
essentially the definition of a basal
state
it's a state that is used as a proxy it
is a state that is used for a variety of
purposes let's say you are a very major
power let's say you are a superpower and
you want to do certain things but you
don't want to be seen to do those things
then you create a puppet state or a
whole bunch of puppet States and you
have them
play various roles and provide various
Services yes and if they do it well and
as long as they're useful for you you
let them Prosper you let them Prosper
look at what Japan Japan was really
prospering into the 1980s until suddenly
somebody pulled the plug on Japan right
so Japan is over South State of the US
it is under its permanent military
occupation of the US South Korea the
same and when it comes to the Chinese
North Korea is China's basal state
so uh this this family this dinosaur the
Kim Dynasty Kim il-sung Kim Jong-il and
Kim Jong-un now these three leaders they
belong to the same family grandfather
father and son yes and
and uh they essentially uh they are
prompted by China obviously and I'm sure
the Chinese have provided provided them
various uh kinds of Technologies yes uh
including ballistic missile technology
which was then passed on to Pakistan via
North Korea
and possibly even the Pakistan nuclear
program uh not possibly definitely some
of it was stolen from the West in the
west knew it they allowed it to happen
because they wanted to counter balance
India and then some of it was provided
by the Chinese as well
so the Chinese I I spoke about this
yesterday they told the Americans that
in in I think 2012 or so when they were
in control of Pakistan when they were
Pakistan's Big Daddy
they said to the Americans that Pakistan
is our Israel we are using Pakistan the
way you use Israel so Israel is another
another American Muscle state in the
Middle East and they use it in a variety
of ways which we're not going to right
now so uh North Korea the Chinese will
prop up the regime the North Korean
regime the Kim Jong-un regime is long as
North Korea is useful and it's going to
be useful indefinitely as long as the
Americans are in control of Japan and
South Korea
and as long as that situation exists
North Korea is very valuable for the
Chinese as an attack dog as a
destabilizing factor as a nation to use
in case of War to to maybe launch
missiles of Japan and South Korea and
all that so the Chinese can be seen as
is having stayed away from all this
their hands are clean the North Koreans
are doing this so it gives you plausible
deniability even though everyone knows
who the real master is and someday it
can be sacrificed to take the blame away
from China like uh Ultimate Warrior is
saying here so yes this is a wasall
state and not all was all states are
used for military purposes
Japan developed so many wonderful
Technologies which the Americans
whatever was useful for them they have
taken yes right now Taiwan is a massage
state tsmc is being stolen by the
Americans now yeah the semiconductor
uh Corporation it is now the the heart
the core of tsmc is now being relocated
to the US which means in a few years
Taiwan will be Expendable maybe in three
years maybe five years and let's see
what how things go by then maybe by 2025
perhaps who knows the Americans are are
doing this very rapidly there's already
one large plant a tsmg plant in Arizona
and the second one and a second world
one is already being built and so on so
that's how you so Taiwan has never been
used as a military base obviously it is
militarized the way Japan is but Taiwan
was used for that purpose and so on so
vasal states are states that are
essentially
victims they are being parasitized on by
a more powerful State and it is being
used in a variety of ways the population
may be very prosperous which is great so
it will keep them quiet yes but the
political class is controlled by the
foreign power the military is controlled
by the foreign power they this nation
has no actual foreign policy and when
the time comes the hammer will fall and
the nation will be destroyed it
eventually will happen
that's the characteristic these are the
characters of a massage date so that's
what North Korea is for China that's
what Pakistan was for about a decade or
so for China now Pakistan is the US is
visal State once again
so that's how the game is played
Daniel Nicholson says is Bhutan India's
de facto was all state if not how
invited India go on to become the
security guarantor of Bhutan could PRC
be possibility of Republic of China
choose Bhutan to base battle theater in
it in a short war with India
of a solid state like I said is a state
that is used against its will
to play various kinds of roles and and
serve various kinds of purposes for the
superior power
now is India using Bhutan in this manner
you know making Bhutan play a certain
role against its wishes
India is not doing that Bhutan uh from
India's perspective is a buffer it's a
small buffer State against China India
wants Bhutan to remain independent and
peaceful and be out of the influence of
China that's all apart from that India
is not utilizing Bhutan or or in any of
the ways that the the Americans for
instance use Japan or South Korea or
Israel or Pakistan and any of the ways
that the Pakistan that the Chinese use
uh use North Korea the India is not
doing the Bhutan what the Americans have
been doing to the NATO States
yeah eu's economy is right now being
crushed the European Union yeah it's
been crushed the economy and so on
um
so India has not done any of that to
Bhutan India needs to be the security
guarantor of Bhutan because otherwise
the Chinese will over in Bhutan and we
will have a new threat where Bhutan once
used to be and do the bhutanis want the
Chinese to do that no obviously not the
Chinese are already nibbling away at
parts of Northern Bhutan yeah they're
already doing that the Chinese are
encroaching on Nepalese territory
they're encroaching in bhutan's
territory they are encroaching on
everyone's territory everyone's scared
of China
and India has never been a hegemony
power that's why Bhutan obviously will
rely on India rather than China as a
security guarantor
whom do you need security guarantees
from from China or from India from
bhutan's perspective they need security
guarantees from from India to safeguard
them from China right so that's what it
is so in the future could the could the
Chinese choose Bhutan as a battle
theater in a short war with India well
it's very hard to use Bhutan as a battle
theater because the bhutanese territory
is extremely mountainous it's very hard
to to do Warfare over there let's take a
look at this right map we need to have a
map
uh at least once or twice in every live
stream so here's the map let's go into
uh Bhutan
so if you see the satellite image of
Bhutan
you will see that it's incredibly
mountainous and and full of forests it's
very hard to do any kind of warfare here
except for hand-to-hand fighting or very
close combat close range fighting yes
you can't drive tanks or or any armored
vehicles here yeah the Peaks are very
high these are the Himalayas so even
helicopter Warfare or whatever will be
difficult and so on so it's very if you
want to if the Chinese want to uh use
another Nation
to maybe make a foray into India they
could possibly in some locations
possibly use Nepalese territory
but Bhutan is is very hard because it's
it's so mountainous yeah and and
forested
uh but yeah the Chinese could definitely
in the future at some point in time but
they feel very confident try to invade
Bhutan and take over parts of Buddhist
territory more than what they're already
doing it's certainly a possibility
so India needs to ensure that bhutan's
territorial Integrity is not compromised
and that's the guarantee that India
essentially whether it is written or not
India has given Bhutan yeah so Bhutan is
is a
India's protectorate
from that perspective
okay vishwa says we need a fighter jet
for INS vikrant the Indian aircraft
carrier the new one we have two in
service right now one is INS Vikram
Aditya which was originally uh called
Baku then it was called Admiral gorskov
and then it was called once we acquired
it from the Russians which is a whole
long lengthy story which I spoke about
yesterday to a certain extent yes
so uh we have this new aircraft credit
which we have built ourselves developed
design and created built ourselves
indigenously and right now the uh this
aircraft area the new one the ins
vikrant is undergoing sea trials yes uh
the sea trials will continue until 2023
or something like that and obviously we
need a contingent of jets fighter planes
for the ins vikrant let's see what ins
vikrant looks like shall we ins week
[Music]
let's put that on the screen ins vikrant
um here we are here we are this is the
aircraft carrier which we have built
ourselves right now as you can see
it has no
fighter planes
on its deck
so yeah some helicopter trials are
happening and there were some other
fighter jet trials possibly also that
may have happened or maybe in the
process of happening but thus far this
fire this this warship has not acquired
has not been given its contingent of
fighter planes so this warship ins
Vikram this aircraft carrier I believe
if I'm not mistaken it can carry about
30 or so roughly fighter planes 30 or so
fighter planes so what kind of fighter
plane would it carry I mean every
aircraft carrier has a certain set of
characteristics so if it's a very large
one it can have maybe 70 80 like the
American aircraft Traders have yeah
maybe up to 100 so it could have a bunch
or a mix of different kinds of fighter
planes the Americans typically have the
fa-18 Hornet and uh some other planes as
well maybe a wax planes maybe a few
helicopters and so on so forth in the
case of the Indian aircraft carrier it
will carry about 35 the planes
and the question is which fighter plane
will be acquired so uh if you look at
this aircraft carrier it has a set of
elevators I think two elevators which
have a certain width so
and and below the deck you will have the
hangars where the planes will be
refitted and refueled and all those
things essentially refitted you know
maintained and all so the maintenance
will happen below the deck below the
deck and then the plane will have to be
brought up on the on the top deck using
the elevator
and the elevator has a certain width
which means that you cannot we cannot
have a plane which is wider than that on
the ins vikrant and that kind of uh you
know tells us that certain planes are
out of the question uh like the F-35 I
believe is clearly out of the question
but anyway we are not acquiring that so
uh
there was supposed to be a a naval
version of the LCS ages and the Navy
said it's too heavy for our purpose so
they've rejected that right now we have
a twin engine deck based fighter te dbf
that is being developed by Hal in the
sun Aeronautics limited that will
I think the trials will the first trials
will happen by 25 to 25 26 27 somewhere
there and it will be inducted finally by
2032 or so the twin engine deck base
Fighter the Indian fighter plane until
then we need to to have some kind of
stop Gap solution one possibility is the
MiG-29 which is already used in the
other aircraft carrier it's a good plane
but it's kind of old it's kind of you
know not not a new not not The Cutting
Edge technology it's a good plane the
MiG-29 that's one possibility the other
possibility is the Rafa Rafael but the
Rafal RAF early that's the French
fighter plane of which we have acquired
36 or so which are which it's a
multi-role fighter plane and it does
very well from aircraft carriers so
that's one possibility and the other
possibility is the American fa-18 Super
Hornet
now which one should we go for
um
maybe not the MiG-29 it's an older
design they want something more modern
even the fa 18 is an older design it's
from the 1970s or 80s or something like
that you look at the look at the history
the rafale is is a very modern fighter
plane and so it's excellent fighter
plane yeah so the the it seems to boil
down to two fighter planes the fa-18 the
Super Hornet which is an American
fighter plane and
different rafale
so which one should we take
that's the question isn't it
um
what which one which one should we
acquire so we would typically want to
acquire about 35 36 aircraft fighter
planes the the vikrant will be able to
carry 30 but let's have a few more so
maybe 30 40. so we acquired 36 Rafal so
maybe another 36 new fighter planes
maybe Rafal maybe F-18 now which one
should we go for should we go for the
French plane or the American plane let
me tell you a story
we like stories
in the 1980s
the Australian Australians
purchased a bunch of fa-18 fighter
planes from the Americans yeah
now this fa-18 fighter plane it has
software it has a Target acquisition
acquisition system
it has a iff thing if Friend or Foe
and it has a Target Target acquisition
system which is the radar and the
software behind it and all that so when
the Australians acquired when they when
the when the fighter planes were
delivered and the Australians tried them
out and all that they discovered
something interesting
when they flew the fa-18 super Hornets
and they said that I want the target
acquisition system to let's say in in
mock combat practice or whatever I want
the the target acquisition system to
lock on to so and so Target when they
did that the target acquisition system
refused to lock onto those targets
essentially what happened is that the
software inside the plane refused to
lock onto targets that the Americans
does not did not designate as targets
let's say the Australians wanted for for
whatever reason to designate a Chinese
aircraft as a Target or maybe let's say
an Indonesian aircraft for for for
argument's sake or some other maybe a
New Zealand aircraft the target
acquisition system would not allow the
plane to do that it would not lock onto
those targets so these planes came
essentially crippled
and the Australians were allowed to use
these planes only for purposes that the
Americans would whitelist everything
else no you can't do it so what's the
point of buying such planes it is
they are they bought these planes I
think in the 1980s 85 86 87 somewhere
there it's only in 2006 or 2007 that
they were able to circumvent the code
and put in their own software package
20 years it took them for for being able
to use the planes properly for whatever
purpose they wanted does India want to
be in that position
you acquire a bunch of American Hardware
a bunch of American planes and then you
can't use them
for what you need to use them for it's
like the the Cargill worth situation the
Indian army was using the GPS system
which belongs to the Americans and when
the the war happened the Americans
Switched Off the GPA system for the
Indian army so suddenly we were not able
to Target things effectively
when you when you use foreign technology
it always comes with a kill switch
they can kill it anytime they want they
can disable it remotely anytime they
want
so that the Russian see we have used
Russian technology for a very long time
fighter planes and all we have never run
into the situation the Russians have
never done this to India I I spoke about
Russia as well yesterday that Russia you
know India has no real friends yeah you
can look at that but um
the Russians have never done that this
sort of blackmail the Americans are
known to do it to their to their closest
allies the Australians Australia is a
U.S corporation Australia is owned by
the Americans Australia is one of the
five IE Nations the U.S and five
Versailles the five English-speaking
basalts and the Australians were treated
like this when they bought American
fighter planes you think India will not
be treated the same way it is dangerous
to acquire any
um critical equipment from the Americans
because they can they can disable it at
a moment's notice when they feel like it
it is dangerous now even the French
possibly could do it possibly
but the French seek
a certain degree of freedom from their
own vasal status the French are the only
nation in Europe in the EU in NATO which
has a certain amount
off of certain degree of Independence in
foreign policy not completely but to a
certain extent it does yeah their
nuclear weapons and nuclear missiles are
not owned by the Americans and
controlled by the Americans they control
it themselves and certain other things
as well they have their own independent
foreign policy in the Indian Ocean to a
certain extent so the French would very
much like to break free
of this this slavery that has been
imposed upon them by the
English-speaking world since the end of
the second world war yes so I would say
that the French deal would be you know
more trustworthy than the American deal
so I would say that uh India should when
it comes to these two choices the fa 18
or the Rafal India should go with the
rafab and I believe that's the direction
in which we seem to be going so my
assessment is that we should go for the
Rafal not for the fa 18 or the MiG-29
because it's the MiG-29 is kind of an
older fighter plane they want something
more modern they they Rafael is great
and obviously
India and France have a significant
amount of strategic convergence and we
have been cooperating in a variety of
ways some which we know of some which we
may not know of and so on so I think
India and France have a certain amount
of understanding certain certain certain
degree of trust to some extent much more
than what India has with the us
so I think India should go for the Rafal
rather than the fa-18 that is what I
would say now it's for the government to
decide but I hope that's
based on what I know it seems to be the
best choice
harshit says what is your view should
India invest in strategic bombers
strategic bombers what say strategic
bomber a strategic bomber is a massive
aircraft massive aircraft that can carry
lots of
very large quantities
of payload ammunition I mean Weapons
Systems cruise missiles or gravity bombs
laser guided bombs smart bombs or
whatever else ballistic missiles 2 can
be launched from strategic bombers so
typically 30 40 50 tons of payload and a
strategic bomber has a very large range
typically seven eight nine ten twelve
thousand kilometers without refueling
typically so certain would certain
strategy bombers whatever without
refueling range of maybe 7000 kilometers
some may have a 10 000 kilometer range
and with refueling you can extend it
even further and so on yeah
should India invest in strategic bombers
so
to answer this I should show you the map
to understand do we need to invest in
strategic bombers
so India's zone of interest is the
entire Indian Ocean region
and our number one threat is China
and when it comes to China
the heart of China is far to the east
most of China is empty most of it is is
occupied territory occupied from Tibet
from the from the oygors and so on the
Real China is in the East this is the
true Han Heartland Beijing is in the Far
East of China so is strong King Chan
Shanghai
Hong Kong and so on yes uh so the
targets of interest for India in case a
big war breaks out between India and
China if we have to neutralize Chinese
high value targets these are all in the
Far East of India
now you could launch ballistic missiles
but I am sure that the Chinese have
certain ballistic missile defenses and
they would guard cities like Beijing Etc
very very carefully
yeah so even if we have Mir you know
mirv equipped missiles but is it
missiles with multiple multiple
independently targetable warheads and
all the Chinese may have uh you know
defenses for that but if you have a
strategic bomba that can fly deep into
Chinese territory undetected
and then launch cruise missiles like the
brahmos for instance which have a very
high velocity then it would be very hard
for the Chinese to defend against that
so that's why and and even when it comes
to a safeguarding the Malacca Straits
for instance or maybe blockading the
Malacca Straits you could you know have
have
strategic bombers take off from maybe in
the Southern India or somewhere else and
then you know carry out operations in
the Malacca Strait maybe we could even
carry out peacekeeping operations
throughout the Indian Ocean if you have
strategic bombers you know
uh there are lots of zones of interest
for India so actually I would say that
strategic bombers make a lot of sense
for India right now all the bombing
Duties are they are carried out by
multi-role Fighters 30 mki the the
Jaguars and so on the mirages and so on
so forth even the mig-20 ones and so on
yeah
so we it would be great for India to
acquire a bunch of long-range strategic
bombers right now all the
all the air assets the bombing assets we
have are theater
assets we need strategic assets a
theater a military theater is a smaller
Zone than a military a strategic area
you know so we need strategic bombers
and uh so that's why I think that India
should uh invest in strategic bombers
and I would say that uh
you know if you want to really study
this in detail uh there is this
wonderful article that I can uh point
you at it is by Rakesh Rakesh krishnam
is a wonderful uh geopolitical analyst
so this article India's Blackjack gamble
does the iaf really need Russia's Tu
topole 160 strategic bombers it's a
great article it explains everything in
great detail you know uh the case for
why we need to we should possibly
acquire this and how many of these
should we should acquire so I I've heard
you know it's it's in the news right now
it's kind of a rumor or kind of possibly
it may actually happen that India may be
in the process of acquiring six tupolev
160 strategic bombers from Russia on
lease possibly yeah six of these six is
a great number so this is an enormous
aircraft it flies at Mach 2 and uh
what's the range I'm sure the range is
uh
what's the range yeah it can fly 20 000
kilometers non-stop with aerial
refueling it has a payload capacity of
40 tons it's a Mach 2 bomber and it can
go essentially anywhere in the in the
Indian Ocean region in the South China
Sea and it can you know go all the way
to Beijing and come back
and deliver a wonderful payload it can
carry 12
heavy cruise missiles brahmos class
cruise missiles it could possibly carry
a whole set of other armaments as well
so I think it makes a lot of sense for
India to acquire this this weapon system
this this bomber yeah because we have
threats from China the Chinese have
their own H20 deep strike bomber the
Intercontinental deep strike bomber that
they are uh on the verge of developing
and they also have
a stealth Shan h6k bomber that uh
that they are deploying and all that so
they there are significant threats
emanating out of China and the Americans
also have their their strategic bombers
and all that so we also should acquire
this one the Russians have modernized
this this fighter plane with this
strategic bomber I think it makes a lot
of sense for India to acquire this India
in the in the past 70 years 70 plus
years of History has never had a
strategic bomber even though it made a
lot of sense for India to have it it's
all because of India's strategic myopia
for the longest time the Indian
political class and the Indian military
establishment also so only China only
Pakistan is the major threat they kind
of neglected the real threat coming from
China it's only now that our Horizons
have properly broadened so I think it
makes a lot of sense to very quickly
soon acquire six of these very powerful
aircraft the thing about this aircraft
is that it can penetrate deep into enemy
territory it fires it flies in
incredibly fast super it's a Mark II
plane twice the speed of sound it has a
Terrain hugging radar which means it can
it can fly very low and just above the
terrain you know maybe 20 30 feet above
the time possibly I'm not sure exactly
what it is but you know it can fly low
stay below the the range of most Radars
and even if it's detected by radar it
has counter measures and it flies at
Mark two so it's really hard to catch up
with it and that Mark II speed coupled
with the Mark II of the brahmos can can
you know deliver a huge amount of of
just kinetic energy momentum you know
apart from whatever the brahmos whatever
Warhead the brahmos will carry so I
think it makes a lot of sense so I would
say if you want no to know all the
answers read this article wonderful
article explains everything yeah so I
think it makes a lot of sense for India
to invest in strategic bombers
um
okay RM says Russia sold fighter
helicopters to Pakistan in 2015. like
like I showed yesterday yes so why can't
India sell weapons to Ukraine
why should we sell weapons to Ukraine
the ukrainians have these this major
benefactor the superpower the Americans
are are pouring in arms and ammunition
and weapon systems into Ukraine for free
yes all they ask is that the ukrainians
fight to the last Soldier
yeah fight the proxy war for NATO
let your soldiers die we will give you
all the weapons you need all the
obsolete Weaponry that you can we can
provide you from NATO from the European
nations maybe even from America from
from the US itself
so if the ukrainians are getting so much
of this why would they seek arms
ammunitions ammunition weapons Etc from
India and the truth is that Ukraine is a
hostile Nation
Ukraine has never been friendly to India
Ukraine has always been anti-india
Ukraine has itself Ukraine so sold tanks
to Pakistan Ukraine has always voted
against India in the United Nations in
in favor of Pakistan
India still had certain military
dealings with Ukraine would you like to
see what what was going on
let me show you
here is an article from Russia Beyond by
the same author Rakesh krishnam yes
wonderful geopolitical analysis so fake
mix missing antanovs Hawaii India must
keep away from Ukraine so the ukrainians
sold fake mix to the croatians defective
migs
and
look at this how can you lose an
aircraft
well you can if you are a Ukrainian
company a major crisis involving Ukraine
erupted in April 2015 when the
ukrainians believe it or not lost 5
Anthony of 32 transport planes belonging
to the Indian Air Force these aircraft
were part of a batch of 40 an32s that
had been sent to Ukraine state-owned
whatever this is utterly export for
upgrades and refurbishment the remaining
64 were to upgrade it to uh the if's
kanpur Air Force Base
under a technology transfer from Ukraine
but the planned upgrade was halted as
Ukrainian Engineers walked out of the
job and supplies of spare parts stopped
uh the iaf brass did not find it funny
they embraced An Almighty fuss and told
the ukrainians find our planes the
anthon of 32s were ultimately found and
flown back to India so the ukrainians
tried to steal five Indian Air Force
planes yes
um a diplomat from the Ukraine Embassy
said told the Indian side that the ifs
must resolve this issue with with the
company the Ukrainian government cannot
help
and the financial portal Zero Hedge
governments we wonder if that was that
rather unhelpful attitude has anything
to do with India not imposing sanctions
on Pakistan and like I said the
ukrainians have been supplying thanks to
Pakistan and all that so I'm glad India
is now staying far away from you from
Ukraine it's a hostile Nation we should
stay away from it and uh well good luck
to them for what's coming
foreign
says what happens if a nuclear submarine
sinks ooh are there any sankan nuclear
submarines in our oceans so first of all
let me tell you that submarines are way
safer than fight than aircraft and how
do we know this
because
there are way more aircraft in the ocean
then there are submarines in the air
so submarines are safer than planes
okay that's that's I I hope you
understand this joke now uh what happens
when a nuclear sub if a nuclear
submarine sinks well if it sinks it's
it's dangerous are there any sunken
nuclear subs in our oceans yes
uh
let's let's find out so let's put a
Google search on the screen and let's
take a look at it together
uh there was a Russian nuclear submarine
called the k278
let's
yes
oh I got the spelling right
the Soviet submarine k278 comes somalets
it was a very Advanced submarine which
uh
which sank in the parenthesis of the
coast of coast of Norway in the late
1980s
and yeah it it was not only a
nuclear-powered submarine which means it
had a nuclear reactor with nuclear fuel
inside I believe it it may also have had
um nuclear weapons on board
did it have a missiles
had missiles did it it carried Torpedoes
and cruise missiles
okay I'm not sure if it was carrying
nuclear missiles at the time but it
certainly had its nuclear reactor so
there was an accident on board and the
things sank and I'm sure many people
many many of the crew perished yes 42
total died
so that's one example so when you have a
sankat nuclear submarine with a nuclear
reactor on board it is a very dangerous
thing you have to well as long as the
nuclear reactor itself is not breached
uh and if it is then then it's still
okay but even then uh
you have to keep on testing the the
waters in the region for any possible
nuclear contamination you know any any
uh radiation that is being that is
leaking out of the thing and if there is
a radiation leak they will you would
have to take Extraordinary Measures to
perhaps you know uh to perhaps Salvage
the submarine or maybe to to intermit in
some kind of casing and ensure that the
nuclear fuel doesn't leak out or
possibly even Salvage the nuclear
reactor it's very dangerous very
hazardous and people will be will get
exposed to nuclear radiation but what
can you do about it
so yes when a nuclear submarine sinks as
long as the nuclear reactor isn't bro
isn't destroyed or is it hasn't breached
the situation is still okay
in the long run you would possibly want
to take out the nuclear reactor in some
in some Manner and and you know take it
out of the ocean but if you can't do it
then you have to keep monitoring the the
entire region
for any
evidence of of radiation leak leakage
and if the nuclear reactor itself breaks
it's a disaster it's a disaster if there
is any leakage any substantial leakage
it's a disaster uh comparable with the
with the Three Mile Island Disaster or
Chernobyl or the Fukushima disaster it's
the same kind of thing you know we don't
want that to happen ever but yes there
have been nuclear submarine accidents
like the one that I've put on the screen
the k278 comes
foreign
let's take some more questions
Ottawa says how is Muhammad bin Salman
so confident in going against the USA
yes he wants to join brics which is
essentially Rebellion against the US
isn't the absolute monarchy too fragile
and volatile and a coup is highly
possible how could he take such a big
risk by the way I'm 17 years old I'm
currently pursuing Bachelor's in Chinese
studies characters are very difficult to
learn and all names and histories sound
the same haha
all the best in your studies sir and
it's good that somebody is studying the
Chinese language and and stuff like that
culture because we need our own experts
vis-a-vis Chinese
understanding of China and all that yeah
so it's great to see that now how is
Muhammad bin Salman so confident in
going against the us there are two
extreme possibilities one possibility is
that he is completely stupid he's making
a suicidal Choice the other possibility
is that he has calculated all the
possibilities very well and he is very
confident that he has complete control
within his country
and he's he's confident that there is no
possibility of a coup against him see in
the Saudi royal family there are lots of
you know claimants to the throne you
know people who who are first in line
Second land third in line tenth in line
that sort of thing to the throne there's
always uh you know this this line
um the line of a line of claimant to the
throne
so uh typically it's the it's the it's
the
first in line who becomes the next king
uh so and obviously when you have such a
situation you will have
you know politics that's being played
behind the scene develop people who are
ambitious and who would like to see
nothing more than the current King being
replaced and possibly me coming to power
in in this in his dead that sort of
thing so it's always a dangerous
situation even in the best of times
so uh when Muhammad bin Salman came to
power
he you know if you recall he had he had
taken a significant number of his family
members hostage in a hotel in a
five-star hotel in a luxury hotel and I
think whatever was engineered at the
time would have ensured that he has
absolute power over the nation yes
so it looks like I don't think he is a
silly person or a stupid person I think
he's a very intelligent person a very
ambitious and determined person person
and it seems it looks like he has done
all the calculations and yes he has seen
what the different threats to him are
and it looks like he has calculated that
he is strong enough powerful enough and
in control enough of his Nation to go
ahead and and try this out you know try
to go against the US and try to become
become a member of brics go towards the
India China Russia side instead of the
U.S side which is a huge huge very risky
thing but looks like he has calculated
that he is going to be able to succeed
in that so let's see how it goes but
it's obviously a very big risk that he
has taken for sure
jaspreet Singh says what's the
difference between the term indoorians
and Aryans because I've seen that these
terms are used interchangeably also how
Aryans scethians and Huns are different
from each other do they have their all
their origins in India before moving out
okay good question
let's take the second part of the
question first no let's how do we do
this Aryans this term aryan aryan the
Aryan term or the indo-aryan term it's a
western construct this term was created
by foreigners
by westerners Europeans it's not an
Indian term yeah the actual term is Arya
a-r-y-a Arya that's what the the that's
the term that was used in the
indo-iranian world
if it is to be used as a
self-designation it can only be used by
the people of Indian origin or Persian
origin and the Persian people were also
descendants of Indians of ancient
Indians and that's why they also
consider themselves to be Arya the
Indians
always use the term Arya as an adjective
that signifies
Superior Behavior
yeah Noble Behavior so a person who
would be called Arya would be a person
who is highly cultured and civilized
it's not it was not used in India as an
ethnic or racial term the Persians used
it as an ethnic self-designator as a
racial term as an ethnic term that we
are the Arya people so it was it no
longer meant Superior or or cultured or
civilized it meant Persian for the
Persian people for the descendants of
the ancient Indians would move to Persia
so the term in the Sanskrit language and
in the old Iranian language which is a
descendant a daughter of the Sanskrit
language the term was Arya a-r-y-a not
Aryan and then the Europeans decided to
mangle it up to to distort it and in
this order using the term Aryan
so the term Aryan
from the European perspective meant the
entire Indo-European language family
people who spoke the European languages
these were all called the Aryan peoples
that's that's the kind of that's how
they used this this made-up term and
then we know the story in the 20th
century early the first half of the 20th
century the the Germans the Nazis they
misappropriated this term and used it
uh to designate the Nordic people the
North European people
and that's how this term uh picked up
this term became associated with Nazism
and racism and all the all all that and
then it became difficult for the
historians the scholars in the west to
keep using the term because for most
people the lay people the term Aryan
denoted Nazi had very strong Nazi
connotations
so then they decided
to start using to to add a prefix so
they added the prefix Indo
so earlier there was a they had created
this this artificial set of families the
language family called the Aryan
languages which are the languages that
are spoken in Northern Western India and
Afghanistan Pakistan
Bangladesh not Bhutan Nepal and so on
yeah now these languages are called
indo-aryan languages
so it's these are all artificially made
up terms these are all eurocentric
Western occidentalist terms these are
not terms that have emerged out of India
or Persia right so that's the so there
is no real difference between indoorians
and audience they just don't want to use
the term audience anymore because it has
Nazi connotations that's why they now
use the term indo-ary but the meaning is
the same from their perspective yes so
there's no real difference it's just
that the the term Aryan is now tainted
even in the U.S the white supremacist
groups they call themselves The Aryans
or whatever the hell it is here
so it's a racist term it's a white
supremacist term it's a Nazi term that's
what they have done to it so now it's
this so now academics and Scholars don't
use it anymore they use the term indoor
Aryan but it has the same meaning yeah
um so that's what it is now um
uh how are the aryan's key things and
horns different from each other so the
scithians so if you are to consider the
Aryan term as an ethnic designator then
if you were to use it in that manner it
means it denotes the people of India and
Persia
so the term Aryan if you want to use
Aryans as an ethnic term it means the
people of India and Persia the skitians
were descendants of ancient Indians
there were lots of migrations of Indians
out of India the one of the first known
migrations is happened as in the
aftermath of the battle of the Ten Kings
in which a whole number of of Elizabeth
clans were evicted out of India because
they lost the battle Yeah that's a whole
different story I will not go into that
so that's one of the first uh known
examples
or instances of Indians
migrating out of India westwards and to
the north of India yeah and then you had
these regions called
let's put it on the screen uttarakuru
what was uttarakuru what was
um so uttar Guru was north of the
Himalayas north of the Kuru mahajanapada
so which essentially means that
uttarakuru was Tibet and present-day
xinjiang which is currently for now
occupied by China that was uttarakuru
the entire uh expanse of of vast expanse
of land north of Nepal and Bhutan and
arunachal and all of that north of
Kashmir not of the dark that was
uttarakuru and present-day Central Asia
which is Kyrgyzstan Uzbekistan
Turkmenistan all of that was
at that time Gandhara was a part of
India which is now called Afghanistan
so the scithians they lived in
uttarakuru and uttara mudra they were
nomadic people they were of Indian
origin they their kings described
themselves as descended from Vedic Kings
right they performed a rituals such as
the show me the yagna and all that for
some time and then eventually their
culture became mixed up with people from
other other parts of the world from
other Central Asian nomadic people So
eventually the scythians became a kind
of mixed player mixed race yeah
but uh culturally they remained very
much Indian they were Sun worshipers
uh even when they fought with the with
the Persians and all that so the
scythians are are descendants of ancient
Indians so which means that if you were
to call Indians as Aryans then the
kitchens were descended from ancient
Aryans the homes were not so at all the
homes originate uh
north of present-day China in the region
that's more or less roughly present-day
Mongolia that's where the homes
originated about two and a half thousand
years before today the Chinese called
these people the xionu
x-i-o-n-g-n-u or something like that
that's that's a spelling uh in in the
Roman alphabet the English alphabet yeah
uh so the Huns emerged from that region
there were warlike people they forced
the kushans and then the skitheans to to
to run westwards and southwards and
that's how the this Keith and kushan
invasion of India happened uh the homes
were an Eastern Asian people they looked
very different from Indians you know the
typical uh Eastern nation features the
so-called the so-called
features right that's what they hones
originally had and then then they also
ruled over large parts of Central Asia
and even Eastern Europe and they also
acquired a mixed ethnicity they mixed
with the people of these regions and
eventually it all become became a big
Melting Pot
so
so the Huns have a different origin a
different ancestry the scithians are
essentially descendants of ancient
Indians which means descendants of
ancient Aryans if you want to use the
term Aryans for ancient Indians so that
is the story
sudipta says could you please explain
how demonetization used to work in
ancient times when a new ruler used to
come and issue his own coins what
happened to the old coins in circulation
very interesting question it's nice to
see a question like this
so listen
um in the old days coins were either
silver or gold
sometimes when times were bad you would
have you know Alloys which is like you
know smaller coins or coins with with
gold that mixed with some other metal
you know slightly cheapened form of the
thing but typically when you had the
great Emperors of India whether it is
the Gupta Emperors or the or the kushan
Emperors or the Maureen Emperors or even
later on you would have typically gold
coins or later on silver coins so the
various mahakshatrapas also had gold
gold coins and later on even even silver
coins so now the value of the coins came
from the precious metal not from
whatever was stamped on top of it yes so
we find lots of coins in archaeological
sites you know sometimes we find pots
that have been buried by people long ago
and then forgotten for whatever reason
or they could not be retrieved full of
coins you find that sometimes you find
coins strewn around here and there you
know people losing coin from their
pocket or whatever so you find coins
lots of coins in archaeological sides
I'm not sure if you have found morian
era coins but we certainly have lots of
examples of kushan era coins you know uh
uh kanishka's coins and and coins of his
later successors you have Gupta Ila
coins which which depict the Gupta
Emperors as it's really muscular ripped
guys you know War like guys also playing
musical instruments and all that and you
find coins of Maha chaturbas like
nahapana Etc all across the place they
found coins of nahapana and in vasudeva
Etc
in in the British islands in the Roman
world in the Greek world and so on so
so the question is when a new ruler is
to come to power what would happen to
the old coins the new ruler would need
to issue new coins with his face on top
of it on the coins right
so what happens so what would happen so
typically the two either one of two
things would happen
they would either take all the coins
back possibly possibly that's one
possibility we don't know we don't have
the records so I I one logically two one
of two things could happen one is you
take all the old coins you melt them up
and then you create new coins with this
with the with the face of the new ruler
on them or secondly you just take the
old coin heat it up and then stamp it
with the you know
stamp it with the face of the neural so
you don't even have to melt it you just
have to put a new face on it and
sometimes you can see the outline of the
old face also on it you know so one of
the examples I can give you is the is
you they have found many coins of the
great great
that have been over struck with the
likeness of the
um
yeah
most likely lived a couple of
generations after nahapana some
historians say that
must have defeated
because that's when you do such a thing
like you know superimposing your your
image on the image of of the older of
the previous King but most likely I
think
lived a couple of generations after
nahapana and maybe he conquered
territories that were at some point in
time ruled by the marks and then he
acquired those coins and he placed he
embosed his own likeness his own face on
top of nahapana's coins so that's the
kind of thing that happened you
typically never threw away old coins
because they were valuable they were
precious metal metal gold or silver so
you would either melt them and create
new new coins or if you did not want to
go through all the trouble you would
simply over strike the coins with your
own image and then it will be used as
your as your own coin so that's the kind
of uh process that would happen
obviously uh India has a history that
goes back thousands and thousands of
years coins have been in use for at
least 2000 years minimum most likely at
least two and a half thousand years I'm
sure that it must have been in use even
before that because we had a Iron Age
copper age Bronze Age all of these
things
so um so yeah that's how it would work
that's how demonetization would work in
ancient times yeah
uh they just says in Ancient India Bihar
was one of the most prosperous places in
India Bihar was a place of ancient
dynasties like Maga demorians and so on
Bihar was a birthplace of Sita mithila
yes for thousands of years Bihar has
been the center of learning as well we
know that so why is Bihar in its current
state why is it not doing so well in
modern times
in the past the whole of India
was incredibly prosperous yes we know
that Bihar was was a fantastically
prosperous place magad after all
partly Putra was the ancient capital of
India for the longest time yes
um it was the capital of the mauryan
dynasty Chandra Gupta maurya Ashoka
morya bimbisar and later samprati and
all that these Kings it was the capital
of the of the shunga Dynasty and his
descendants it was the capital of the
Gupta Empire the Gupta dynasty and so on
so
it's been in a way one of the one of the
most prosperous and most important parts
of India many empires emerge out of
there partly Buddha is one of the
greatest cities of ancient India and
obviously a place of learning we had
great vision you know universities like
like nalanda and all that
many more I'm sure so what happened to
Bihar what happened to Bihar is what
happened to all of India we had
takashila far to the West
of
of magadh all the way in gandhar
prakashila was a great University great
center of learning the great uh
mauryan
um what shall we call him the great
mentor of the more in Emperor
chandragupta who Chana
who was from magadh he taught in
takshashila in gandhar we know that
so India was interconnected all of India
was incredibly prosperous think of
gandhar itself it was a place of
learning you have so many biharas and
stupas there and you had the great
University of a lot of prosperity as
well think of a place like saurashtra
saurashtra was was the Gateway to the
West for India during the time of the
great rulers
saurashtra was incredibly prosperous
because we had the great ports in
saurashtra through which trade with
Egypt and the Greek world and the Roman
world would be carried out and that's
why it was the that's why the Gupta
Emperors decided to take over the Russia
from the from the indusgetians from the
chatrapas think of Kalinga Kalinga was
incredibly prosperous in a great Center
of arts and culture and learning think
of Sri Lanka it was called Golden Lanka
what happened to all these places
everything was destroyed by the Invaders
and occupiers
firstly but the Turks and then by the
Europeans and everything of value was
stolen out plundered out of the Indian
subcontinent
that's why all these in and think of
Bengal vangadesh Bengal was possibly the
British described Bengal as the most
prosperous province of India obviously
they saw it from their perspective
but Bengal was indeed incredibly
prosperous
yes
and it was a it was a great place of
learning and culture and look at Bengal
today
whether you talk about East Bengal or
West Bengal look what's happened there
is there any Prosperity so what happened
first of all you had a thousand years of
foreign occupation which destroyed
Prosperity all across India
all of India was incredibly prosperous
one-third minimum of the entire Global
GDP came from India India accounted for
at least a third of the entire world's
GDP if not more most likely it would
have accounted for more than half of the
entire world's GDP if you go back two
and a half thousand years because there
was nothing else in the world apart from
small places like Egypt Egypt was
minuscule compared to India Rome was
insignificant compared to India from the
terms of GDP
look up Angus Madison's research don't
trust me
yeah so what happened is the Europeans
destroyed India the first the Turks
destroyed India and what was left was
destroyed by the Europeans
India
became
we know what happened yes completely
destitute famines hundreds of
artificially engineered famines and so
on so that's why things are like this
and then after Independence so-called
Independence we have the nehruvian era
and then we had various state
governments I'm not taking anybody's
name yeah I'm in various parts of India
who were not interested in in in
progress in development
and so on
so that's what happened to various parts
of India including Bihar very sad and
it's time that we get our act together
when Bihar is one of the greatest parts
of India
today unfortunately in some parts of
India people make fun of uh Indians who
come from up and Bihar that is horrible
up has been the ancient Heartland of
India Kashi is the epicenter of Indian
civilization for thousands of years more
than 10 000 years in Bihar magadh is one
of the great power centers of India and
the great place of learning and culture
and advancement we would like to see
interpretation you in Bihar regain the
great Glory which they always had so
it's time we we start doing that you
know
um
Arnav Carpenter says how can we say that
the famines during the British rule were
engineered by the British
because there are many famines before
British arrival which killed Millions
how are those famines different from the
ones doing British rule what data do you
have to Pro to claim that there are many
famines before the British arrived if
you look at uh historians of the
writings of stories like arthi majumdar
and others
you will find that before the British
arrived in India in the past 2000 years
before the British arrived in India
there were three major famines three
of course there were periods of drought
caused by the El Nino
phenomenon and all that and yet India
never had famines
there were a couple of families during
the Mughal rule the turkic rule because
of mismanagement and all that but why
but before this this before the
Millennium of humiliation India almost
never ever had famine show me the record
right you're making a claim without any
evidence
I invite you to show me the evidence of
famines that killed millions of Indians
before the Millennium of immigration
show me evidence
yes the burden on proof of proof lies on
the person who makes the claim I am
telling you there were no such violence
maybe one or two in maybe three in two
thousand years
now
um
and and how is it that there were no
famines despite the El Nino phenomenon
despite uh sometimes you have this
periodic uh bouts of drought why were
there no famines because Indians knew
how to manage food grains let me give
you an example
let me give you an example
here here we are
this is a tweet of mine okay Saraswati
civilization grains silos from 7380
belief uh
7380 DC
look at the size of these grain silos
see you can see a human being squatting
next to it these are incredibly large
grain silos I think it's from or
something yeah
these silos have been dated through
carbon dating of organic Trace materials
to 7380 BC
and these are enormous grain silos you
can you can store grain that will last
you for several years so even
nine and a half thousand years before
today Indians knew how to safeguard
their grain they had they were
cultivating grain in large quantities
and they they would have enough grain in
storage that could you know safely keep
people
well fed for for several years
so Indian rulers and Indian Society
always have this it was impossible to
have a famine in India that's how well
managed the entire system used to be
even 9 000 years before today
so in a society such as that if a famine
happens
it's only it can only happen if it is
artificial engineered
and it's only after the British came to
India that suddenly famine started
happening every year every single year
in every path in various parts of India
famine after famine after famine if you
add up the total of the death toll of
these famines you come
you you will reach a figure close to 100
million Indians who died in this
artificial Farmers so please educate
yourself
let me not
sale it really annoys me to see these
questions but I understand why it is so
so it's because our education system
hasn't given us the right perspective it
has not given us the true the facts yeah
has
those of you who are watching have your
history textbooks taught you that we had
proper Family Management systems for
thousands of years that even during the
service
we had these systems in which you had
these massive grain silos that could
store grain that could feed people for
for several years not just one year but
several years we had these systems in
place it was impossible to have famines
in India it's only when the British
arrived and they saw that the Indians
fight so well and then they refuse to to
give up so they decided that the best
way to defeat the Indians is to starve
them if you are hungry if you're
starving how will you fight that's what
they did so please I beg you educate
yourselves and stop having this
inferiority complex and stop blaming
yourselves you are the victims blame the
oppressor not the victim
foreign
what was the story history of human
sacrifice is it present in Ancient India
also did Native Americans know Human
Sacrifice on a very large scale
historians always say this but I find
some I want some hard evidence to
support this narrative you know there is
no evidence of human sacrifice in India
some random accounts here and there you
will always find some criminals doing
something Criminal
in a
in a society which is the world's
largest Society the world's largest
geographical area of one civilization
you will always have there's always some
criminal elements in society you can't
portray that as ritualized human
sacrifice if they murder somebody yeah
so what's the history of human sacrifice
there have been lots of cultures that
have practiced Human Sacrifice but much
of it is propaganda for instance when
Julius Caesar
uh conquered the British Islands
the British Isles the first of all
conquered Europe Western Europe from the
Celtic people then he conquered the
British Isles too and he wrote this
wonderful account in Latin which is now
used nowadays used as a textbook for a
textbook or for learning Latin
so uh he wrote about the Celtic people
the Golic people and all goldish people
and he said that these people they
practice the barbaric human sacrifices
the vicar man they put they put
the victims in this huge star this vicar
statue of a human being and then they
burned them alive
there is no evidence that this actually
happened but that's what Julius Caesar
wrote maybe it was done to justify his
conquest of these people and to portray
them as inferior barbaric people so it
was it was it is all right to conquer
such people and maybe Massacre a few
million of them yeah
so Human Sacrifice definitely has
existed much of it may be propaganda but
in some places you obviously have human
sacrifice but the funny thing is that
when see for instance
in Europe
in the Middle Ages the Medieval era
the the most popular book in Europe at
that time
in in the Middle Ages was the malayos
malefica room
the Hammer of the witches it was a
manual on how to accuse somebody a woman
of being a witch how to identify the
identifying characteristics and how to
torture her to death
and hundreds of thousands of European
women were accused of being and
they were either burned alive or
tortured to death is this not
state-sponsored religiously ordained
human sacrifice
so human sacrifice was very much
prevalent in Christian Europe
and the manual was the malayus
the most popular book in Europe during
the Middle Ages
imagine that yeah so that is human
sacrifice
um so when something like this happens
in the west they portrayed something
else but when when when let's So In some
cultures you have war and you have
execution you take business and
sometimes prisoners are executed
yes uh let me uh if I can find it you
know
one second my neck called
let me
um shackle the skeletons let me show you
an image you may be disturbed so in case
you are Disturbed please don't look but
yeah it's an image of skeletons all
right
it's from Greece
would you consider this to be human
sacrifice
this is about 2000 years old if I'm not
mistaken some something like that
so over here it says that the Shackled
skeletons Unearthed in Greece could be
remains of slaughtered Rebels so in this
case this is not a human sacrifice even
though they have clearly been all
Shackled together and slaughtered It's
Not Human Sacrifice it is just a
execution of rebels
yeah it's a mass grave look at the
horror of this of this scene
so when it's done in Europe it's it's uh
it's it's not a human sacrifice or
something but when it's it's done in in
in Asia perhaps or among the North
American people the Native Americans
then they would classify that as as
evidence of a backward primitive
barbaric brutal culture that sacrificed
human beings
it's very likely that you had Wars
people would take soldiers who were
taken prisoner in war and then they were
executed do you remember what happened
in chittorgar
Akbar the Great
besieged chittor
eventually the women committed johar
they had to commit johar because they
did not want to be captured alive or
dead by the Turks
the men went out and did the Saka and
they fought to the last man they all
died and then the defenseless population
of the city thirty thousand
non-combatants unarmed civilians men
women children
thirty thousand men women children were
executed in one day
is that human sacrifice what what
exactly how would you characterize that
so it's certainly possible that the
North Americans the Native Americans
they would have had conflicts between
various Clans and tribes and all that
and sometimes they would capture some
people and then maybe they would be
executed or whatever would you
characterize that as the outcome of
warfare or would you characterize that
as human sacrifice so in many cases when
non-europeans are involved
many of these cases of warfare of
execution have been labeled incorrectly
with prejudice deliberately as human
sacrifice yeah so Human Sacrifice
obviously uh
when you execute somebody that's I mean
sacrifices typically when you are doing
it for some God or something I'm not
sure how how prevalent that was in in
the ancient world I think lots of the
so-called cases of human sacrifice may
actually be executions of criminals
possibly
or or Rebels or soldiers captured from
the enemy or whatever yeah and in some
cases there may actually be human
sacrifice so it's it's a mixed bag I
think uh executions and all that would
have existed as long as the human
species has existed yeah but the the
claim that Native Americans did human
sacrifice at a very large scale is
absolutely lies absolute lies
not true at all
I would say that Native Americans were
more civilized than the Europeans who
destroyed them
all right and in India there is no such
no history of human sacrifice none
whatsoever until the Turks and the
Christians the Europeans came in then it
all happened because we had
at the hands of the Christians the
Portuguese you had the
the Goa Inquisition the barbaric inhuman
brutalities that they perpetuated on
innocent Indians men women children in
the name of the religion yeah that that
is that is human sacrifice yes so the
foreigners
the Turks and the Europeans have indeed
perpetrated such atrocities in India on
Indians but Indians
what does Indian culture tell you
whether the dharmic culture Hinduism
Buddhism Etc it says Dharma
non-violence is the highest
uh ideal yes so yes violence
unfortunately has to be resorted to in
self-defense or for righteous causes but
non-violence is the greatest ideal
that's what we say that's what our
culture has always believed in and there
is no concept of sacrificing a life to a
god
sometimes yeah in some cases such
certain rituals have emerged where you
sacrifice certain animals to God and all
and and yes when times were bad there
were certain kuld devis goddesses would
demand human sacrifice of your enemies
in order to appease her so certain
rajput Clans had certain Kula devis like
like chamunda or Kali and to appease to
to please
you would have to offer her human heads
But Not Innocent human heads
Not Innocent human heads the heads
of the of the evil doers you if you if
you killed in an innocent person and
offered that person's head to the
Goddess that would not give you any
benefit she would not be pleased with
that
according to the belief right she wanted
the heads of evildoers of the enemies of
the people so yeah so I would not
consider that to be well truly Human
Sacrifice or in in an evil sense
yeah it's it's like getting rid of of
The Barbarians who have invaded your
society and they want to destroy your
culture and your people so yeah that's
the deal so India overall does not have
any real history of human sacrifice no
history of sacrificing sacrificing
innocence or killing innocence not at
all but in other parts of the world yes
in Europe you had that and so on so
forth yeah it's a whole so it's a it's a
very big topic you know you could have a
month-long seminar you know program of
seminars
and discuss this in very great detail
so many more questions that I have but I
will not be able to take them let me
take some questions now from the live
chat as always I am not able to take all
the questions I've selected so let me
take some questions from the live chat
if you have questions from live chat do
ask me
all right
archaeologists are trying their best uh
to claim that a teenage girl excavated
in Peru was a human sacrifice yeah
that's the mainstream General consensus
that that girl who was discovered in
Peru she was essentially mummified
because of the cold and the dry weather
they say that she was given some kind of
hallucinogen some kind of drug
uh to consume and then she was strangled
and left on a mountain top or something
yeah that's that's that's what they do
claim
uh what else
uh akshit Kumar yadav says why not
Russian fighter planes well get the best
possible fighter plane you have right so
uh if you want 36 fighter planes to take
off from your from your uh aircraft
carrier let's consider the options we
have the MiG-29 which is an older like
like a third generation
third yeah most likely third generation
fighter plane second or third third
third generation fighter plane from
Russia it can take off and land from an
aircraft carrier deck the the newer ones
that sukhois
Etc are too large they can't take off or
land from aircraft carrier decks they
they are not suitable for the role is
there any other Russian fighter plane
that fits the bill not quite so
so the only candidate is the MiG-29 the
competition for the MiG-29 is let's say
the fa 18 The American or super hornet
in the rafale if you consider all these
planes all the three the most modern one
is the Rafal it's a 4.5 generation
fighter plane very advanced fighter
plane far better than the fa-18 and far
better than the mid-29 so why not go for
the best one we have the money we have
the money so why not get the best
possible bang for your buck
so that's why that's what I'm saying I
have nothing against Russia or they're
fighter planes the fighter planes do
well the mig-29s are good planes but
they're not the best and we can afford
the best
so so that's the reason why I said not
that all right um
what else do we have do we have anything
interesting
[Music]
um
Indian fashion history I I wonder why
our historians don't write about this
don't research this
if you look at various Indian sculptures
all across the length and the breadth of
the Indian subcontinent from various
time periods
for let's say the kushan period the
Gupta period the Maha period the the
Indus Ethan period the uh Chola period
the Tola Dynasty the the chera period
the vijayanagar Empire we have so many
sculptures in in on on the walls of
temples most of them are still found in
the South the northern ones are all gone
destroyed by barbarians yes but we still
find lots of evidence you know and we
find these cave paintings of Indian men
and women ladies and gentlemen wearing
various kinds of uh you know designer
outfits you could say
such incredible Fashions we had and not
a single God damn Indian historian has
bothered to catalog this and write about
this
it's it's so disappointing that our
historians are good for nothing losers
and they are abdicating the duty and
they're wasting our
money and our time
writing antirestral garbage so yeah you
know
we have we have a very ancient history
of fashion
it's something that you know I I mean I
would have to put lots of images on the
screen and speak about them but yes it's
something that I would invite you all to
look at just look at ancient images of
cave paintings from ajanta ellora other
places yes look at various sculptures we
had on on the walls of temp temples and
other monuments we get incredible
examples of ancient fashion very stylish
especially the fashion that ladies use
you know the kind of hairstyles they had
the kind of dresses they wore various
styles of sarees very the kind of
ornaments in jewelry they wore in in the
cave paintings you see the kind of
bright colors they used to have and the
fact that dark skin was considered to be
beautiful incredible there is so much to
explore India is like a gold mine
for historians sociologists and so on
but they refuse to
do that so I hope some of you will go on
to do that in the future
uh let's take one more question because
we are almost at the end of today's
um
today's episode
let's see
yes they had sandals they had sling bags
they had you know high high platform
sandals kind of things you know those
those you know people who are slightly
shorter they wear this this thick souls
and all
so that sort of thing in sling bags they
had mirrors and they were very
interesting very interesting fashion we
had
various kinds of dresses they used to
wear
my prediction for India in 2023 India
wins India Rises India keeps Rising
India keeps progressing India keeps
doing well
and will it will get stronger that's my
prediction for India in 2023
uh
I guess that's that's that's about it
yeah I think that's it for today yeah so
thank you so much for all the questions
it's always fun maybe we should have one
one session that is simply live chat
questions that I take only from the live
chat that would be interesting that
would be like it would perhaps give you
more more
uh
more options of asking questions yeah
more opportunities so maybe I'll do that
next week possibly I think the World Cup
final is on Sunday the next Sunday one
week from now maybe I could do a live
stream when I did in which I take
questions from the live chat while
commentating on what's happening in the
World Cup maybe maybe I'll think about
that maybe yeah so let's let's do
something like that soon until then take
care thank you so much as always for you
for all the questions for your
participation for your support for your
viewership thank you so much very
grateful always very grateful until next
time take care and I will see you very
soon thank you bye good night good day
take care